<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Glossary on TMC - Pygame Zero</title>
    <link>https://digitech.nfshost.com/pgz/glossary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Glossary on TMC - Pygame Zero</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language><atom:link href="https://digitech.nfshost.com/pgz/glossary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>argument</title>
      <link>https://digitech.nfshost.com/pgz/glossary/argument/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitech.nfshost.com/pgz/glossary/argument/</guid>
      <description>When calling a function, the values given to it are called arguments. For example, in this case:
total = add(3, 4) 3 and 4 are arguments to the function add().
When defining a function, the pieces of information that the function takes to do its job are called parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>co-ordinate system</title>
      <link>https://digitech.nfshost.com/pgz/glossary/coordinate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitech.nfshost.com/pgz/glossary/coordinate/</guid>
      <description>In most programming environments (such as Pygame Zero), the screen co-ordinate system uses (x, y) co-ordinates, with the origin (0, 0) in the top left corner of the screen, with x to the right, and y going down.
Everything to be displayed on the screen must be rastered, which means rendered into a grid of colored pixels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>color/colour</title>
      <link>https://digitech.nfshost.com/pgz/glossary/color/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitech.nfshost.com/pgz/glossary/color/</guid>
      <description>In almost all programming, American spellings are used. So as programmers we use colors, even though we would normally spell the word colours.
For most programming, colors are described by the amount of red, green, and blue light to emit. These numbers are normally in the range 0-255. In Pygame Zero, we list these as a tuple (red, green, blue), such as:
(0, 150, 255) You can use the Google Color Picker to find different colors, and then copy the RGB value listed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>parameter</title>
      <link>https://digitech.nfshost.com/pgz/glossary/parameter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitech.nfshost.com/pgz/glossary/parameter/</guid>
      <description>When defining a function, the pieces of information that the function takes to do its job are called parameters. For example, here:
def add(first, second): return first + second first and second are the parameters of the function add().
When calling a function, the values given to it are called arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tuple</title>
      <link>https://digitech.nfshost.com/pgz/glossary/tuple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitech.nfshost.com/pgz/glossary/tuple/</guid>
      <description>A tuple is a single unit of data made up of multiple values. In Python they are defined using round brackets, with commas separating the values. Tuples can contain all sorts of data as values, but in Pygame Zero we use them most often for colors (red, green, blue) and co-ordinates (x, y).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
