<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Glossary on TMC - Gemma</title>
    <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Glossary on TMC - Gemma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language><atom:link href="https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>argument</title>
      <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/argument/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/argument/</guid>
      <description>When calling a function, the values given to it are called arguments. For example, in this case:
total = add(3, 4) 3 and 4 are arguments to the function add().
When defining a function, the pieces of information that the function takes to do its job are called parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>color/colour</title>
      <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/color/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/color/</guid>
      <description>In almost all programming, American spellings are used. So as programmers we use colors, even though we would normally spell the word colours.
Colors are slightly different on the Gemma from most other programming environments. For most programming, colors are described by the amount of red, green, and blue light to emit. These numbers are normally in the range 0 to 255. In Python, we list these as a tuple (red, green, blue), such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>import</title>
      <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/import/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/import/</guid>
      <description>Importing is the process of adding functions from additional libraries to support your program.
Imagine we wish to use the randint() function to choose a random number between 1 and 6, as though we were throwing a single six-sided die.
The randint() function is included in the random library, but there are three ways we can import it, and each has its attractions.
import    1 2 3 4  import random num = random.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>list</title>
      <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/list/</guid>
      <description>A list is a data structure for storing a series of related pieces of information.
 Defining a list Selecting elements Adding elements Removing elements   Defining a list    You can define a list using square brackets, with the elements separated by commas, like this:
squares = [0, 1, 4, 9, 16, 25, 36] vowels = [&amp;#34;a&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;e&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;i&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;o&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;u&amp;#34;] Selecting elements    You can pick an element from the list like this: squares[0].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>parameter</title>
      <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/parameter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/parameter/</guid>
      <description>When defining a function, the pieces of information that the function takes to do its job are called parameters. For example, here:
def add(first, second): return first + second first and second are the parameters of the function add().
When calling a function, the values given to it are called arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tuple</title>
      <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/tuple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/tuple/</guid>
      <description>A tuple is a single unit of data made up of multiple values. In Python they are defined using round brackets, with commas separating the values. Tuples can contain all sorts of data as values, but when programming Gemma we mostly use them for colors (red, green, blue, white).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>type</title>
      <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/type/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/type/</guid>
      <description>Computers store all information as sequences of numbers, but different kinds of data are encoded in different ways. For example, whole numbers and decimal numbers are stored differently.
Some common data types you&amp;rsquo;ll encounter are:
 integers (int) Integers are whole numbers, and can be positive or negative. floating point numbers (float and double) Floating point numbers (commonly called floats) are for storing decimal numbers. The number is stored in scientific notation, with a mantissa and exponent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>variable</title>
      <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/gemma/glossary/variable/</guid>
      <description>A variable is a named place to store a piece of information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
